NOT LONG AFTER
THE CROWN PRINCE RETURNED HOME,
HE FELL ILL AND DIED
HE BLED FROM HIS EYES,
EARS, NOSE AND MOUTH
AND APPEARED TO HAVE DIED
FROM POISONING
JUNE 27TH, 1645
ANNALS OF JOSEON DYNASTY
- Thank you.
- Sure.
Did you prepare for the test?
I should quit drinking. It doesn't help.
We can become rich
if we work as royal physicians.
They're hiring acupuncturists
this time, right?
Hwang, who got into the palace last year,
bought a house.
How many rooms in his house?
It's a mansion.
I should have been nicer to Hwang.
Why?
You're taking the test too?
- Yes. I'd like to try.
- Right.
Kyeong-Soo,
you should try to get rich too.
Of course! Kyeong-Soo can get rich!
- Finish up.
- Sir.
Prepare for the visit.
Yes, sir.
He's here! Hurry up!
Greet Sir Lee Hyung-Ik,
the head royal physician.
It's an irregular pulse.
It could be a sign of pregnancy.
He is low on energy.
If he doesn't get acupuncture treatment
now, he could die.
Shall I treat him?
This thread is different
from what I normally use.
I think he is sick in the mind
rather than the body.
Sir, how about trying acupuncture?
I've seen enough.
I believe he had a stroke.
How dare you talk out of line!
Are you blind?
How do you know that?
I heard him walk with a limp earlier, sir.
As his breathing is short and irregular,
his hasty and impatient personality
must've brought on the stroke.
How can you diagnose him
without feeling his pulse?
It's nonsense
to feel the pulse with thread, sir.
How dare you!
It began as a means
to avoid touching the ladies of the court.
In truth, we must talk with patients
to make a diagnosis, sir.
How would you treat him with acupuncture?
Here! Over here!
Throw it!
Brother!
I warned you not to run, didn't I?
You did it!
Congratulations!
You got a job in the palace.
Kyeong-Soo, you'll be rich!
I knew you would make it someday!
He always worked so hard.
Try it.
Good things happen
to those who live honestly.
Of course!
Here you are.
What? Is there a problem?
No. Thank you.
Why are you always so patient?
When I become a royal physician,
everything will be fine.
Here, eat.
- Delicious, isn't it?
- Yeah.
When I return from the palace,
I'll buy a house, treat your illness,
and everything will be good.
Gyeong-jae, I won't be able to come back
from the palace for a while.
Why? For how long?
I'll have lots to learn at first.
I'll come back in a month or so.
But after that, I can commute from home.
You said that when you went to find herbs
in the mountains too.
Yes, but it took longer
because you wanted mountain roots.
I had to find those too.
You feasted on the roots, remember?
Are you okay, Gyeong-jae?
Why you!
When I get paid, I can clear my debts.
Please give me a month.
Then come back in a month!
You know Gyeong-jae will die
without the herbs!
Out!
You already owe me so much!
Make sure you take your medicine
when I'm not here.
I have no one else but you.
Don't worry, I'll be back.
Just wait for a month.
In the palace,
you must pretend you didn't hear
or see anything.
I guess that doesn't apply to you.
Anyway, you must watch your mouth
at all times.
I guess they fancy handsome men.
Don't mind them. Women find me attractive.
Isn't the palace the other way?
This is a new shortcut.
Let's go.
It's this way!
If you must answer, just say yes.
In the palace, there are places we can go
and places we must never go,
so pay careful attention.
You must never
go near the high ladies of the court.
Be careful.
This is the royal clinic.
The medicine cabinets are over there,
and that's the storage room.
Right. You can't see.
Come this way.
Here, have a seat.
That's good.
Just wait here, I'll bring your uniform.
- Let's finish up and go for lunch!
- Coming!
A newcomer mustn't touch the medicine!
You don't even know what it is!
Don't be so rough on him.
He touched the poison.
He didn't know it was poison.
I'll warn him. Let it go this time.
That little boy has some temper!
Jeez.
Have a seat.
Sit down.
As we work to save lives here
at the royal clinic,
order of rank must be upheld.
- But…
- What?
Why is there poison here?
To make a potion for executions.
Sorry.
Here, have some.
You must be on night duty every other day.
I don't sleep much,
so I'll help you the first few times.
Don't worry.
Please sleep if you're tired.
What? I never sleep on night watch.
I'll read a book over there.
You don't need the light, right?
I'll turn the lights off.
He has such keen senses.
Women find him attractive?
Cordyceps, styptic weed…
Gyeong-jae, it is cold at nights.
Are you doing well?
It feels as if we've been apart
for a fortnight now.
Everyone here in the royal clinic
are kind and good to me.
I have meat served in all my meals
and am very comfortable here.
Come this way.
The east gate is to the right
as soon as you come out.
Don't worry, he's blind.
Rookie, sort all the herbs here.
Understood?
How can a blind man do that?
It's to teach him a lesson.
I'll buy some food
and be home in two weeks.
Don't forget to take your medicine
and stay healthy.
- Why do you seem so excited?
- What?
No, I'm not.
There are only a few days left
until the Crown Prince's return.
The Crown Prince went to Qing
as a hostage for…
Eight years.
The Crown Prince's son
has never seen his parents.
No wonder he has that disorder.
A disorder?
Only people of the royal clinic know.
Prince Suk-Chul
still wets his pants at age ten.
You mustn't tell anyone!
Yes, sir.
I'm here for Lady Cho.
She has a severe stomach ache.
Lady Cho?
I'll call a royal nurse right away.
No need.
We have a blind acupuncturist.
What are you doing? Bow to Lady Cho.
Are you the new acupuncturist?
Yes, Your Highness.
Follow me.
My lower abdomen feels cold
and I can't digest my food.
I'll treat her abdomen
with acupuncture, sir.
You may do so.
Will you take all night?
You've found a good acupuncturist
this time.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Your Highness,
the Crown Prince has left Uiju.
I guess my body is reacting
to the Crown Prince's return from Qing.
Chills happen from worrying too much.
It's best not to worry, Your Highness.
I'm not worried about me.
I'm worried about my son.
This is from His Majesty.
There.
Did you see?
If you tell anyone you saw me,
you'll be punished.
- Prince Suk-Chul!
- Sir!
Prince Suk-Chul!
- Prince Suk-Chul!
Have you seen the Prince?
I am a blind man.
Prince Suk-Chul!
Where are you?
Is it true that you can't see anything?
Yes, sir.
Since when?
I've been blind since I was born, sir.
Then you've never seen
your parents' faces?
No, sir. I can't see anything.
Prince! Where are you?
- Prince Suk-Chul!
Is the restorative ready?
I heard my father will be here soon.
It's ready, sir.
If you give it to him,
I'm sure the Crown Prince will be pleased.
This is Cheon, the acupuncturist.
Sir, here's the restorative.
Let's go. Hurry!
Why isn't anyone here for the welcoming?
Grandfather!
His Majesty, the King,
is lying ill in bed.
If he is too ill to welcome
the Crown Prince after eight years,
as the Premier,
I must check His Majesty's condition.
Follow me.
If you dare take one more step,
I'll have you beheaded.
His Majesty is ill!
Why is the royal physician out here?
This is the royal chambers.
You should see to the matters
of the council hall.
If the Premier
cannot check on the King's health,
I shall have to resign.
Please enter, sir.
The Crown Prince
and the Qing envoy have arrived, sir.
Please go and welcome them.
Qing rules the world now, sir.
And the Crown Prince
has come with Qing's blessing.
Is it not a joyful occasion, sir?
Your Majesty,
the Crown Prince has arrived.
My son.
I am your mother.
Son.
Mother.
My son.
Father.
Your Highness.
Where is my father?
Make way for His Majesty!
Well done, my son.
Make way for the Emperor!
I've brought the Emperor's edict.
Crown Prince…
Come and translate.
My father has knelt down.
How could I?
The translator should…
Come here.
What is the savage saying?
- He says I must translate.
- Now.
What is the King saying?
Tell me what he said!
Your Highness.
Please translate
before it escalates further.
I did not come here
to be disrespected like this.
I shall leave at once.
I'll do it.
"If I recall what you did to me
at Namhansanseong eight years ago,
"I should dethrone you
as the king of Joseon."
"Know that my generosity is only
at your son's earnest request."
Those are gifts. Take good care of them.
Yes.
Your Highness.
Take those things inside.
Put that in the second room.
She's so pretty.
She hasn't changed at all.
Is your love interest here, sir?
What?
You scared me.
That was dangerous.
How could His Majesty
call the Qing envoy a savage?
The Qing envoy speaks Korean well.
He spoke in his language
because he wants us
to recognize that Qing is above us now.
It appears the eight years
you spent in Qing
wasn't wasted, sir.
Your Highness.
You must prepare for a new era.
A new era?
As Ming fell and Qing became
the new master of the world,
Joseon must quickly accept it
and adapt to the times.
Everything must be changed
or else Joseon will fall.
It is up to His Majesty to make changes.
Are you aware
of the harvest this year, sir?
Many people are starving to death
in the countryside.
Your Highness.
Please take charge for Joseon's sake.
Are you suggesting
that I oust my father and take the throne?
Of course not, sir.
However,
I suggest that you be prepared, sir.
What did he say?
What will you do now?
If the road is blocked,
we must make a new one.
This is how our land really looks.
From here, people come in ships to Beijing
to exchange goods and books.
See?
This is Joseon.
This small land is…
Is that what the savages taught you?
Father…
Qing has accepted the Western culture
and is growing every day.
Please don't hold on to the past
and try to look to the future.
Do you not know why
I'm dressed in these robes?
Are you still angry about
what happened eight years ago?
What?
"Still"?
Listen…
We must follow Ming.
That's how we regain our legitimacy
and protect Joseon's future.
Ming is ruined now.
I witnessed it in Beijing.
Father, please think of Qing as a friend
and accept new cultures.
That is the best way for Joseon and you,
Your Majesty!
Do you really not know
what is best for me?
Think of Qing as a friend?
We must change.
If we don't…
Joseon will fall to ruin.
You…
Your perceptions have changed.
Still can't sleep at night
because of the coughing?
I'm all right.
Keep a trusted, royal physician close by
and get it treated.
I heard about you from my son.
He said you took good care of him.
I just did my job, sir.
His Highness has become weak
from the long journey.
Will you treat His Highness?
I, your humble servant,
shall do my best, sir.
Thank you.
Cheon is the acupuncturist
who will help me treat you, sir.
I see that he is blind.
Mother.
They say the blind
are better at acupuncture.
How did you know that?
Treat His Highness well.
Yes, Your Highness.
I'm the court maid So
who serves the Crown Prince.
Is the royal physician inside?
He has left the palace, ma'am.
His Highness is coughing a lot.
Come with me.
I cannot treat anyone alone.
That is the rule.
Is the rule more important
than treating the sick?
Follow me.
I know my lungs are damaged.
Can you cure them?
I am but an acupuncturist, sir.
Is there something you'd like to say?
No, Your Highness.
Tell me.
Will you turn a blind eye
to a patient's illness?
Your body is very hard and stiff, sir.
Excessive worrying
prevents good blood circulation.
Please unburden your mind to recover, sir.
Open the windows.
I think my cough has subsided.
I shall bring in the light, sir.
My father, the King…
His hands have become quite cold.
Will you treat him for me as well?
How dare a humble man like me
treat His Majesty?
I'm asking you to.
Yes, Your Highness.
Thank you.
Now, I'll insert one in your neck
to relieve your stress, sir.
Wait.
You can see.
No, Your Highness.
Are you trying to fool me?
I dare not, Your Highness!
Will you keep lying?
I'm done being treated by him.
Let's go.
Follow me.
If you can't see,
how did you write letters to your brother?
Your Highness,
I know it's hard to believe.
I can't see in the light,
but I can see somewhat in the dark, sir.
I deserve to die,
but without me,
my sick brother will die, sir.
Please forgive me.
Why did you claim
you can't see when you can?
People don't want a blind man
to see things, sir.
How old is your brother?
Pardon?
He is ten years old, sir.
He's the same age as my son.
What would you do?
Sir?
You said I have an ailment in my heart.
What can be done to cure it?
Your Highness,
forgive me for speaking out of turn.
Will you keep pretending
you don't know and can't see?
Sometimes it's healthier
to pretend not to see, sir.
Do you mean that
I should become a blind man?
There's no need for someone like you
to pretend to be blind, sir.
Humble people like us must pretend
like we don't know anything and can't see.
That's how I was able to come here, sir.
You are ill because you can see,
and try to set things right, sir.
Court maid Seo,
turn off the lights.
It's a magnifying glass.
You wrote so many incorrect letters.
To become a royal physician,
you must learn to write properly.
Though it's better for your health
to not see or take any action,
sometimes we must see and take action.
Not only that,
we must keep our eyes wide open.
I'm pleased
your coughing has subsided, sir.
I've prepared some medicine
to lower your mild fever, sir.
As my physician is exceptional,
my illness seems to have
vanished out of fear.
- What?
- Is this right?
Acupuncturist Cheon…
As his condition improved,
His Highness has sent you a reward.
It's a precious medicine
for heart disease from Qing.
It will help treat
your younger brother's illness.
You're faster than I thought!
Don't forget me
when you're more successful!
You're going home in two days, right?
Look!
Nice! You have medicine
to cure your brother!
Father! Hurry!
I'm a great writer just like you, Father!
Still, isn't the Crown Prince
on good terms with Qing?
If the Crown Prince sides with us,
Qing will agree to what we want.
My dear son, did you sleep well?
Well done.
Where is the royal physician?
Royal physician!
The Crown Prince has fallen ill
and is unconscious!
It's malaria.
Do you have the East Asian orixa
from Qing?
Yes.
- Decoct it now!
- Yes, sir.
We must bring his fever down.
Wet some silk cloths for me.
Over here!
Yes, sir.
Silk cloth! Hurry!
What are you doing?
Give me the cloth.
Sir?
Do you need another silk cloth?
Your Highness.
Your fever has subsided.
You can rest safely, sir.
- Hurry.
- Yes, ma'am.
We finally brought his fever down.
He just fell asleep.
Bring him the decoction
first thing in the morning.
Yes, sir.
Thank you for your hard work.
Good work. Go to your quarters and sleep.
Is His Highness still asleep?
What is it, sir?
I saw someone jump out
and run from His Highness' window.
- Find him.
- Yes, sir!
It's urgent! Wake up!
Please wake up!
What's happening?
Hurry!
Stop! Gather around!
Acupuncturist Cheon!
How could this happen?
I…
Acupuncturist Cheon!
I must see for myself!
Step aside!
How could this happen?
Step aside at once!
Make way!
It's a royal command.
No one is allowed inside.
Why, you fool!
Father!
Prince Suk-Chul!
Father! No!
Father!
He had symptoms of malaria,
so I wiped him with silk clothes
to lower his fever
and performed acupuncture.
- Malaria?
- Yes, sir.
When he became stable,
Cheon and I saw him fall sleep and left.
Is what he says true?
Yes, sir.
If it was merely malaria,
why was he bleeding
from his eyes, nose, ears and mouth?
Why did his face turn black?
This poison is from the royal clinic.
His symptoms were similar to
those that arise from using this!
Someone must've used this
to poison the Crown Prince to death!
I saw a man running away, sir.
Who did you see?
Tell me everything you saw.
Worried about His Highness,
I went to check around ten o'clock.
Then I saw a man jump out the window
and run from His Highness' chambers.
He cut himself
on a hinge as he jumped out, sir.
It's true, sir.
We found blood on a hinge.
You mean he is the one
who poisoned the Crown Prince?
Under the circumstances,
whoever was injured
must have poisoned him, sir.
Your Majesty.
We must inform Qing at once.
You promised Qing the Crown Prince
will succeed to the throne, sir.
If we don't tell Qing
about the Crown Prince's death,
the humiliation at Namhansanseong
could happen again, sir.
Your Majesty!
Royal physician!
- Treat His Majesty now!
- Yes, sir!
Your Majesty…
It appears he has Bell's palsy.
Cheon! Did you bring your needles?
Yes, sir.
Quickly insert needles
around his chin and cheeks.
Yes, sir.
Lock all the gates
and find the man with an injured leg.
I'll catch that bastard
and rip him to shreds!
- What is the meaning of this?
- Come out!
Stand in a line!
We must find the injured man!
Search every one of them!
LEE HYUNG-IK IS THE ONE
WHO POISONED THE CROWN PRINCE
THIS IS THE POISONED NEEDLE THAT HE USED
Your Highness!
What happened?
The Crown Prince has been poisoned.
What?
But the blind acupuncturist has…
What are you doing?
Your Highness!
Who ordered this?
- Your Highness!
- Please!
Let go of them at once!
Let go of me!
- Your Highness!
- Let go!
Your Highness!
You expect me to believe this?
Your Highness.
Lee Hyung-Ik took care of my son.
Why would he poison the Crown Prince?
But…
Your Highness.
Is anyone there?
He inserted poisoned needles
into His Highness.
There will be poison on that.
I got injured
when I went back to save the Crown Prince.
Do you mean that you can see?
I can see somewhat in the dark.
His Highness
noted my hard efforts to write
and bestowed this to me.
By any chance,
have you seen the magnifying glass
I brought from Qing?
At last, it has found its rightful owner.
He knew that I had some sight
and kept it a secret.
Why would I poison someone
that I'm grateful to?
Lee Hyung-Ik poisoned him?
Yes, Your Highness.
I'll take this letter to His Majesty.
I'll call if I need you.
Meanwhile, stay hidden
and try not to get caught.
Yes, Your Highness.
There are a hundred or so
that we have yet to check.
The guards are out
checking each person here.
- Make haste.
- Yes, sir.
Wait.
Do you work in the royal clinic?
Have you been examined?
What is your name?
I asked for your name.
What are you doing there?
His Majesty's showing
symptoms of paralysis.
- Let's go.
- But, sir…
I must examine him now.
Did you not hear me?
His Majesty must be treated!
Yes, sir.
I will insert needles down the spine, sir.
You may do so.
This abalone soup was sent
by Her Highness' family.
Your Majesty,
you must stay strong at a time like this.
The paralysis could be
because of your having low energy, sir.
How could I eat a healthy dish
at a time like this?
I mean no insult, sir.
Reduce my meals by half from now on.
I shall also write the eulogy myself.
Inform the secretariat.
Yes, sir.
You are a good acupuncturist
even though you're blind.
Or aren't you blind?
You will be my acupuncturist from now on.
I am very honored, Your Majesty.
The Crown Princess has arrived.
Enter.
Are you all right, dear?
You must stay strong at a time like this.
Think of your son.
What is that?
It is a letter given to me by a witness.
A witness?
What witness?
What do you mean?
Lee Hyung-Ik did not see the killer
but the witness, sir.
Crown Princess Kang,
what nonsense is this?
It's Lee Hyung-Ik!
He poisoned the Crown Prince.
He framed the murder on the witness!
I'm being falsely accused.
It's not true, sir!
The poisoned needle was on his head.
It's yours, isn't it?
He dropped a poisoned needle?
That sloppy fool!
Take the needles out.
What are you doing?
Yes, Your Majesty.
Who is the witness?
Bring him to me.
The witness is…
The royal physician
didn't do anything wrong.
I was with him, sir.
Really?
Tell me.
Who witnessed it? Tell me at once!
Well…
God…
Dear…
Tell me, who is it?
Why…
His Majesty is asking you something.
Your family sent the abalone?
Taste it.
- How can this be?
- Guards!
Poison in His Majesty's meal?
Guards!
Arrest that wench at once!
See?
That evil wench
tried to poison her father-in-law!
He was your son!
That wench must be punished!
How could you?
How could you do that?
We must notify Qing
of the Crown Prince's death now!
Will that save the Crown Princess
from the false charges?
We must find the culprit first.
Who else would it be? It must be Lady Cho.
We must clear the Crown Princess' name
and throw Lady Cho in jail!
We don't have any evidence to do that.
You dropped a poisoned needle?
How could you?
You asked me to trust you.
You even hired a blind man for this!
What happened?
Don't be so loud!
What did the witness see?
What will we do if he talks?
Explain yourself!
- Tell me…
- Stop!
They'll hear you!
You're so loud!
They'll hear you outside the gates!
Your Majesty.
Speak softly! Whisper!
What are you doing?
People will be suspicious
if they see me with you.
I'll send orders by letters.
Leave at once.
Scram!
Hurry!
By the way,
did you burn all the letters I sent you?
Yes, Your Majesty.
You're not keeping them
to blackmail me later, are you?
I wouldn't dare, sir.
If things go wrong,
I'll arrest your old mother and children.
I'll gouge out their eyes
and cut off their tongues.
Mother!
Prince Suk-Chul!
Son!
- Son.
- Mother.
- It's all right. Don't worry.
I'll ask Grandfather to save you.
- Grandfather will…
- No! You mustn't!
Never go to the King.
- Go to the Premier.
- Sorry?
What do you mean?
- Not the King.
- Leave, sir!
- Prince!
- Mother!
- Let go, sir!
The blind man saw everything.
Tell him the blind man saw everything.
- Mother!
- Son!
My lady! Court maid Seo…
Wait, I will return soon!
Royal physician!
Sir!
Court maid Seo is critical
after being interrogated!
- Please save her!
- A physician should be there now.
There is no one, sir! Please help her!
I beg you, sir!
All right.
Go and wait.
I'll be there soon.
You…
- It's you!
- Sir.
You're the one
who killed the Crown Prince!
Court maid Seo is hurt because of you!
You can see!
You lied to me!
Can you see?
Did you see everything?
I heard from my mother.
What did you see?
Tell me what you saw!
Lee Hyung-Ik
poisoned the Crown Prince, sir.
His Majesty is the one
who gave the orders.
That's a lie!
I shall go and ask Grandfather at once!
No, sir! No, Your Highness!
Then you'll be in danger, too!
Grandfather killed my father?
That's impossible.
If you go to His Majesty now,
you and the Crown Princess will die.
Let go!
His Majesty has been lying to you!
When your mother found out,
he locked her in jail.
You saw everything.
Why didn't you testify?
Let's go!
Tell them everything you saw!
Because you didn't tell them what you saw,
my mother is in prison.
It's all your fault!
I have a younger brother who is sick.
If I talk about what I saw, he'll die.
Humble people like us need to pretend
we don't see anything to survive.
That's how I have survived
to get to where I am now, sir.
I met my parents after eight years,
and now, my father is dead,
and my mother is in prison.
Now, I have no one.
I've spent my whole life
without seeing my mother.
You said
you haven't see your parents either.
Please save my mother.
His Majesty, the King,
is the one behind this.
What can I do, sir?
Sir!
Sir…
Now what?
The King is the culprit,
but we can't arrest him.
Wait. What about the Premier?
Who will believe a blind man as a witness?
Right.
And there's no evidence.
Still, you must live.
There must be somewhere you can hide.
This is from His Majesty.
What are you doing?
The silk.
Silk?
I saw him receive something.
Wait.
I think I saw something.
USE A POTION THAT INCREASES BODY HEAT
MAKE IT APPEAR LIKE MALARIA
THEN POISON HIM
Grandfather ordered Lee Hyung-Ik
to poison my father.
The blind man told me.
A blind man?
His Majesty sent this letter
to Lee Hyung-Ik.
This is not His Majesty's writing.
Yes, it is Grandfather's writing!
Grandfather.
Why can't I write well?
See? I can't write well either.
But you wrote that with your left hand.
I saw you.
He wrote it with his left hand.
I saw it.
This can't be used as evidence.
Grandfather wrote this.
Why isn't this evidence?
There's no way to prove
that His Majesty wrote it.
Not unless he writes something
with his left hand in front of people.
I can make
His Majesty's right hand go numb.
Do you realize what you just said?
Bell's palsy can't be healed
with one acupuncture treatment.
The numbness must have worsened by now.
I'll pretend to treat him
and make his right hand go numb.
Please find an excuse
for His Majesty
to write something with his left hand.
Are you suggesting that I gather soldiers
and start a rebellion?
I am just an acupuncturist, sir.
I must trust a blind man
and change the King of Joseon?
Hurry!
Why did you change your mind?
It's to save my life, sir.
Thank you.
What brings physicians here at this hour?
His Majesty must receive acupuncture now!
No one informed me.
Lee Hyung-Ik sent the acupuncturist
to treat you, Your Majesty.
Now?
He says if you don't get treated,
the numbness will spread, sir.
Your Majesty.
The secretariat is here for the eulogy.
He may enter.
What is wrong with my hand?
I can't grab the brush.
It's a natural symptom
from treating your illness, sir.
- As time passes, you'll slowly…
- Forget it.
Take it out.
Your Majesty.
If I take it out, the numbness will spread
throughout your body.
Take it out!
If I take it out, you may not be able
to use your arms and legs forever.
Your Majesty.
I don't mean to rush you,
but the sun will rise soon, sir.
The numbness in your right hand
is part of the healing process, sir.
The first memorial rite
must be done before sunrise, sir.
I know. Wait!
I need to grab this to write!
Damn.
- I've something to report to His Majesty.
- He is receiving acupuncture now.
What? From whom?
You!
Who told you to treat His Majesty
without my permission?
What?
I just received orders
to come and treat His Majesty.
Who sent you the orders?
You said he sent you here, didn't you?
He's the one
who poisoned the Crown Prince, sir.
Come closer.
What is your name?
It's Cheon Kyeong-Soo, sir.
Kyeong-Soo…
I'll ask you only once.
Who ordered you to do this?
All the nerves in your body
pass through here, sir.
If I insert it any deeper,
you could die, sir.
Send everyone away!
Why you little…
Everyone out.
- Guards…
- Your Majesty!
Arrest that wretched fool!
Get him!
Arrest that fool!
That way!
Hurry!
He could cause problems later.
Do you understand?
Find him now!
Get down lower.
- Get down.
We have 500 soldiers
assembled outside the palace.
Everything is ready, sir.
What about the eulogy?
The King found out.
However, Cheon took it and ran away.
- Ran away? Where?
- I'm not sure, sir.
We agreed to meet at the council hall.
Let's go there, sir.
No, sir.
We can't trust the blind man.
We could lose our heads.
Send the soldiers away now, sir.
He's here! This way!
This way!
What happened?
Well done.
The King is missing.
The King is missing?
He must still be in the palace.
Where else would he go?
We'll look for him, sir.
Go to the chief guarding the west gate.
Tell him I sent you and he'll let you out.
The Premier sent me.
What is happening?
It's complete chaos.
The Crown Prince passed away and now this?
I'm so scared.
- Quiet!
- Prince Suk-Chul is sick, too.
So royal physician Lee Hyung-Ik
ran to him.
You son of a bitch!
Damn blind fool! How dare you!
Sir!
Suk-Chul.
For a blind man,
you run around well like a rat.
Pretending you can't see or hear.
Just staying quiet as an acupuncturist.
Why get involved in something like this?
Give me the eulogy.
Who ordered you to do this?
Was it that bastard, the Premier?
Did he tell you to kill me
and bring him the eulogy?
Or was it the Crown Princess?
She coaxed my son
to kill me and take my throne.
Now, she plans
to have him sit in my place?
What did she tempt you with?
Did she promise
you'd be the head royal physician?
Speak! Tell me who ordered you!
Who ordered you to kill me?
Did you come here to find me?
Or did you come here to hide, sir?
Premier.
You have a poker face.
What are you thinking?
It's difficult to read you.
You don't look too well, Your Majesty.
If you step down now,
I'll spare your life.
What?
I'm your king!
How can the king step down?
Have you forgotten
who put you on that throne?
That's right!
Then why plot with the Crown Prince
to kill me!
Young scholars have assembled
outside the city gates.
Who'd serve a king
that killed his own son?
You'll use them to dethrone me?
Then what?
Think the savages will let you live?
What if they want to kill us all
and place a king from their land?
Premier…
Listen…
We must band together.
How many years do you think I'll live?
When I die,
the world will be yours anyway.
What if you change your mind?
How can I trust you?
Then…
Whom shall I choose as my heir
for you to trust me?
Lady Cho's son…
It can't be him.
Then you make the choice
from one of my sons.
What will you do with the Prince?
If we let him live,
he'll want to avenge his father's death.
Like a blind man should,
close your eyes to survive.
No one poisoned anyone.
The Crown Prince died of malaria.
Take the Prince and treat him.
Sir…
But I saw it.
His Majesty ordered Lee Hyung-Ik
to poison the Crown Prince.
The Premier has the evidence.
I clearly saw it.
Now, the King wants
to kill the Prince too.
I saw it.
I clearly saw everything.
How could a father kill his own son?
That wretched bastard!
Don't stand there and listen to him!
Take him away and behead him at once!
I clearly saw it.
I saw everything.
What are you doing?
Didn't you hear me?
Behead him at once!
I saw everything.
Take him away now!
What are you doing? Take him away at once!
You dare defy my royal command?
No one defies me.
Arrest him and kill him!
Now!
Kill him! That's a royal command!
Kill them all!
Kill him!
What are you doing? Behead him now.
You saw what happened.
You know what the King did.
How dare they…
Look at those damn eyes.
Damn bastards.
Damn eyes!
How dare you!
Please have this while you wait.
Here.
Have you heard?
The King has fallen critically ill.
- Really?
- Yes.
So they're looking for
a great physician to heal him.
- Really?
- Yes.
Oh, my.
Bastards…
Stay away from me…
Your Majesty.
This acupuncturist is known
to even heal dying cows, sir.
I will check your pulse, sir.
I don't trust anyone.
You…
You've come to kill me.
Guards.
Guards!
I will treat you, sir.
Who ordered you?
Who ordered you to kill me?
Not again.
Guards!
You…
You fool…
I am… the King.
I am the King, you fool…
What do you see, sir?
What is the cause of death?
It's malaria.
THE NIGHT OWL